<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2pub on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</title>
    <link>/tags/2pub/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2pub on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/2pub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter ReFarming</title>
      <link>/post/winter-refarming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/winter-refarming/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful time of year&amp;hellip;
In this landscape so liberally sprinkled with almond flowers, one can almost believe the legend of almond trees in Algarve. Beautiful, but also challenging, in that Good Stewardship of these trees and the soil in which they grown involves a lot of work that needs doing in the short winter season, when days are short and weather unpredictable.
in keeping w/ my new years resolution, am trying to use this blog as my FarmDiary link to my observations log at farmOS link to my Imgur account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chuva de Amendoas</title>
      <link>/post/chuva-de-amendoas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chuva-de-amendoas/</guid>
      <description>So: it started yesterday pm…
here’s the same (almost) image at imgur
 Then in the end, we got an actual rain, so we packed up, went home and ate almonds 😄
ps: here’s a link to the full imgur archive pps: great help from visiting Belgians; you guys were great, thanks! ❤️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frameworks for ReFarming</title>
      <link>/post/frameworks-for-refarming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/frameworks-for-refarming/</guid>
      <description>Eliot Coleman’s “REAL Organic” Standards -condensed:
First, for uncompromised nutritional value all crops must be grown in a biologically active, fertile soil attached to the earth and nourished by the natural biological activities of that soil. There are so many important soil processes that we could not replace even if we wanted to, because we are still unaware of all the benefits they contribute. Second, soil fertility should be maintained principally with farm-derived organic matter and mineral particles from ground rock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homage to James Lovelock</title>
      <link>/post/homage-to-james-lovelock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/homage-to-james-lovelock/</guid>
      <description>On the occasion of his 100th birthday, what to do?  Funny: i had just been thinking of the man, when YouTube’s recommendation engine (whose advice i only take while making breakfast, as a rule) threw me this selection- James Lovelock CCLS2019 -from the Cambridge Climate Lecture Series. Turned out to be a discussion about JL and his theories, with the great man only present via 3 short video segments, so for much of the rest, i paid only partial attention.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>