<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wl on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</title>
    <link>/tags/wl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wl on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/wl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus: OKRs and GTD</title>
      <link>/post/focus-okrs-and-gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/focus-okrs-and-gtd/</guid>
      <description>In fulfillment of my commitment to &amp;ldquo;Measure What Matters,&amp;rdquo; i&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken to develop a program for implementing the system of OKRs laid out in that book -following the implementation timeline pictured above.
This is going to involve a lot of work on my part -the kind of work i don&amp;rsquo;t generally enjoy, which involves a lot of chasing after people and their deliverables- but i&amp;rsquo;m committed to it. Problem is, my way of working doesn&amp;rsquo;t lend itself so well to doing this, SO&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch ReFarmer.Net</title>
      <link>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time. My public blog is out there, but rather an embarrassment, in need of some cleanup &amp;amp; all-around love&amp;hellip; And i need to be pushing out coms right now, in the directin of achieving Collective Impact, while asserting my identity as ReFarmer #1.
MEANWHILE: I must use this dev platform for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, to develop both my chops as a writer, and the technology to support my craft. Simple as it is, this UI and taxonomic model, i don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how it will work over time as a useful writers notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORID revisited</title>
      <link>/post/orid-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/orid-revisited/</guid>
      <description>When (in a previous life, it seems :-) i served on the Board of ICA Canada, our conversations followed a certain pattern that i want to replicate here -just to see where it leads.
OBSERVE what is, here-and-now, without judgement 05:30am here at home, Sunday following week of GROW conference in Lisbon. Ate my usual breakfast, did a full round of TaiChi (without a hitch, muscle memory is coming back), am now drinking tea and watching video of Greta Thunberg -that 16 y/o Swedish climate activist who started the &amp;ldquo;Fridays for Future&amp;rdquo; protest movement- testifying at US Congressional hearing a few days ago (a long session that i couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite get through, but here an edit with just Greta&amp;rsquo;s comments).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji list</title>
      <link>/post/emoji-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/emoji-list/</guid>
      <description>This comprehensive list seems to work almost perfectly&amp;hellip;
But i can only see myself using a tiny subset, i.e.:
 Reactions: 😃 , ❤️ , 💤 , 👍 , 👎 , ❓, ❗️ , Farm-related: 🐔 , 🐑 , :donkey:  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomy Development</title>
      <link>/post/taxonomy-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/taxonomy-development/</guid>
      <description>To make this site into a useful rsource, even just (especially!) for myself, i need a taxonomy (i.e. Categories and Tags, essentially… Plus any ancillary elements in the site navigation: menu bar, sidebar, naming conventions, etc.) that will make it easy to find (i.e. search and filter) content whenever i need it quickly.
Key concepts under consideration:  Categories are mandatory and mutually exclusive; each post must be assigned to one and only one category  cool: just discovered i can change a cat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merlin Mann’s advice</title>
      <link>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</guid>
      <description>Best advice i ever heard for wanna be bloggers came from a guy whose stuff i used to lap up eagerly, every morsel he ever released, until he went silent quite some time ago (he’s still alive -i’ve checked- i think he just got tired of his own schtick). The man is Merlin Mann, and this came from a presentation he did entitled “How to Blog” -which video i did see, a good few years ago; can’t find it now, but i did find his SlideShare deck -notes from which are cribbed below, because i don’t wanna lose this stuff, it’s important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit in which we do</title>
      <link>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It matters not what you do so much as the spirit in which you do it&amp;rdquo;
a little brown man in a bedsheet, can&amp;rsquo;t remember which one
Once upon a time, i fell in love with a woman -and when it became quite serious, i got a hand-written letter from this woman&amp;rsquo;s best friend, in which she wrote: &amp;ldquo;This woman you claim to love, she is like fine crystal: Beautiful, as you know.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>