<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Private on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</title>
    <link>/tags/private/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Private on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/private/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch ReFarmer.Net</title>
      <link>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time. My public blog is out there, but rather an embarrassment, in need of some cleanup &amp;amp; all-around love&amp;hellip; And i need to be pushing out coms right now, in the directin of achieving Collective Impact, while asserting my identity as ReFarmer #1.
MEANWHILE: I must use this dev platform for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, to develop both my chops as a writer, and the technology to support my craft. Simple as it is, this UI and taxonomic model, i don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how it will work over time as a useful writers notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShorDurPerSav</title>
      <link>/post/shordurpersav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shordurpersav/</guid>
      <description>This discipline prescribed by Julia Cameron (and there are many variations on the theme proposed by other writers down the ages) is one i commit to follow. During those hours when i alone am awake in the house , instead of just browsing the endless buffet of offerings from others, i believe that i do well to express my own thoughts -or else be silent.
One thought that occurred to me earlier is: all those people that i look forward to interacting with today (and not without trepidation [1]) are gatekeepers of some technology that i hope to adopt and bring to bear on the challenges i&amp;rsquo;ve taken on for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merlin Mann’s advice</title>
      <link>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</guid>
      <description>Best advice i ever heard for wanna be bloggers came from a guy whose stuff i used to lap up eagerly, every morsel he ever released, until he went silent quite some time ago (he’s still alive -i’ve checked- i think he just got tired of his own schtick). The man is Merlin Mann, and this came from a presentation he did entitled “How to Blog” -which video i did see, a good few years ago; can’t find it now, but i did find his SlideShare deck -notes from which are cribbed below, because i don’t wanna lose this stuff, it’s important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit in which we do</title>
      <link>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It matters not what you do so much as the spirit in which you do it&amp;rdquo;
a little brown man in a bedsheet, can&amp;rsquo;t remember which one
Once upon a time, i fell in love with a woman -and when it became quite serious, i got a hand-written letter from this woman&amp;rsquo;s best friend, in which she wrote: &amp;ldquo;This woman you claim to love, she is like fine crystal: Beautiful, as you know.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>