<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on ReFarmer.Net</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on ReFarmer.Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation 1</title>
      <link>/post/data-visualisation-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-visualisation-1/</guid>
      <description>Until i can figure out how this business of Shiny app publishing, i guess i&amp;rsquo;m stuck with the old-school method of saving graphics out of RStudio and pasting them into documents, like this post.
My workflow on this operation is:
 copy the image of plot as visualised in RStudio; paste it into my desktop image editor, to make any needed adjustments; upload it from there to Imgur.com, which is the best online image host i have found; then paste code Imgur provides for my choice of image rendering size into the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app publishing</title>
      <link>/post/shiny-app-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shiny-app-publishing/</guid>
      <description>Met this morning with Franceso (my R dev collaborator and coach), and we got our Shiny app working well enough that i am very keen to publish it on the web. Much easier said than done! It&amp;rsquo;s pretty bandwidth intensive, as it is crunching a pretty large volume of data, and shinyapps.io just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem up to the task.
So we&amp;rsquo;re looking for alternatives. Only one i know about right now is rpubs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging in RStudio</title>
      <link>/post/blogging-in-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blogging-in-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>I started this blog in a hurry back in January… And since then, i forgot how i did it!
Took a bit of rummaging around, to reacquaint myself with all elements of the technology stack, which includes:
 RStudio Blogdown (RStudio addin, output thru Hugo framework, Lithium default theme) Github.com (free account) Netlify.com (another free account, connected to the former)  It then took a few hours of study and play, to get the software configured and myself trained to the point where i can blog as efficiently as in Wordpress -so now i can freely appreciate the significant advantages of this file-based system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>