<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on ReFarmer.Net</title>
    <link>/categories/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on ReFarmer.Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Soil Test Methods &amp; Tech</title>
      <link>/post/soil-test-methods-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/soil-test-methods-tech/</guid>
      <description>Having experimented with many forms of soil testing over the years, from simple DIY jar tests to the most sophisticated lab tests and everything in between, i can’t say as i’ve yet found a method that is both sufficiently rigorous AND agile enough that we can commit to doing on a broad enough scale and long enough timetable to inform good decision-making here on the farm.
That being said: this “Sector Mentor for Soils” app looks pretty promising on the face of it -and comes well-recommended by my Regrarians Workplace colleague Stephen Barrow, so i might give it a try…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REAL Organic Standards</title>
      <link>/post/real-organic-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/real-organic-standards/</guid>
      <description>While government-approved organic certification standards are a good thing to have, they are by no means a guarantee that the produce under the label is of the highest nutritional quality. Indeed, as anyone who&amp;rsquo;s seen the film &amp;ldquo;Keeping the Soil in Organic&amp;rdquo; must admit, the standard -at least in USA (i.e. USDA Ceritified Organic)- is so broad as to admit of some very unhealthful practices&amp;hellip; And because those practices are essential to the profitiability of those big agri-businesses that have lobbied successfully to protect them, they are in fact coming to increasingly dominate the organic food supply chain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>