<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ReFarmer.Net  ::  Developer Version</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter ReFarming</title>
      <link>/post/winter-refarming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/winter-refarming/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful time of year&amp;hellip;
In this landscape so liberally sprinkled with almond flowers, one can almost believe the legend of almond trees in Algarve. Beautiful, but also challenging, in that Good Stewardship of these trees and the soil in which they grown involves a lot of work that needs doing in the short winter season, when days are short and weather unpredictable.
in keeping w/ my new years resolution, am trying to use this blog as my FarmDiary link to my observations log at farmOS link to my Imgur account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus: OKRs and GTD</title>
      <link>/post/focus-okrs-and-gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/focus-okrs-and-gtd/</guid>
      <description>In fulfillment of my commitment to &amp;ldquo;Measure What Matters,&amp;rdquo; i&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken to develop a program for implementing the system of OKRs laid out in that book -following the implementation timeline pictured above.
This is going to involve a lot of work on my part -the kind of work i don&amp;rsquo;t generally enjoy, which involves a lot of chasing after people and their deliverables- but i&amp;rsquo;m committed to it. Problem is, my way of working doesn&amp;rsquo;t lend itself so well to doing this, SO&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Impact</title>
      <link>/post/collective-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/collective-impact/</guid>
      <description>So this is a popular theme with me these days, which i&amp;rsquo;m touting to anyone who will listen. Mentioned it to Barbara at the Biovilla workshop last week -must followup in writing with her, if she ever answers my email of day before yesterday- was bending HugOli&amp;rsquo;s ear about it all day yesterday, as it needs to be the focus of our ERC&amp;hellip; and it&amp;rsquo;s really the motivation of my OKRs project here on the farm, as we are trying to build a culture around Results That Matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch ReFarmer.Net</title>
      <link>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/launch-refarmer-net/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time. My public blog is out there, but rather an embarrassment, in need of some cleanup &amp;amp; all-around love&amp;hellip; And i need to be pushing out coms right now, in the directin of achieving Collective Impact, while asserting my identity as ReFarmer #1.
MEANWHILE: I must use this dev platform for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, to develop both my chops as a writer, and the technology to support my craft. Simple as it is, this UI and taxonomic model, i don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how it will work over time as a useful writers notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORID revisited</title>
      <link>/post/orid-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/orid-revisited/</guid>
      <description>When (in a previous life, it seems :-) i served on the Board of ICA Canada, our conversations followed a certain pattern that i want to replicate here -just to see where it leads.
OBSERVE what is, here-and-now, without judgement 05:30am here at home, Sunday following week of GROW conference in Lisbon. Ate my usual breakfast, did a full round of TaiChi (without a hitch, muscle memory is coming back), am now drinking tea and watching video of Greta Thunberg -that 16 y/o Swedish climate activist who started the &amp;ldquo;Fridays for Future&amp;rdquo; protest movement- testifying at US Congressional hearing a few days ago (a long session that i couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite get through, but here an edit with just Greta&amp;rsquo;s comments).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShorDurPerSav</title>
      <link>/post/shordurpersav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shordurpersav/</guid>
      <description>This discipline prescribed by Julia Cameron (and there are many variations on the theme proposed by other writers down the ages) is one i commit to follow. During those hours when i alone am awake in the house , instead of just browsing the endless buffet of offerings from others, i believe that i do well to express my own thoughts -or else be silent.
One thought that occurred to me earlier is: all those people that i look forward to interacting with today (and not without trepidation [1]) are gatekeepers of some technology that i hope to adopt and bring to bear on the challenges i&amp;rsquo;ve taken on for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-Heart Tree Surgery</title>
      <link>/post/open-heart-tree-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/open-heart-tree-surgery/</guid>
      <description> Open-Heart Tree Surgery   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chuva de Amendoas</title>
      <link>/post/chuva-de-amendoas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chuva-de-amendoas/</guid>
      <description>So: it started yesterday pm…
here’s the same (almost) image at imgur
 Then in the end, we got an actual rain, so we packed up, went home and ate almonds 😄
ps: here’s a link to the full imgur archive pps: great help from visiting Belgians; you guys were great, thanks! ❤️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji list</title>
      <link>/post/emoji-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/emoji-list/</guid>
      <description>This comprehensive list seems to work almost perfectly&amp;hellip;
But i can only see myself using a tiny subset, i.e.:
 Reactions: 😃 , ❤️ , 💤 , 👍 , 👎 , ❓, ❗️ , Farm-related: 🐔 , 🐑 , :donkey:  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frameworks for ReFarming</title>
      <link>/post/frameworks-for-refarming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/frameworks-for-refarming/</guid>
      <description>Eliot Coleman’s “REAL Organic” Standards -condensed:
First, for uncompromised nutritional value all crops must be grown in a biologically active, fertile soil attached to the earth and nourished by the natural biological activities of that soil. There are so many important soil processes that we could not replace even if we wanted to, because we are still unaware of all the benefits they contribute. Second, soil fertility should be maintained principally with farm-derived organic matter and mineral particles from ground rock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homage to James Lovelock</title>
      <link>/post/homage-to-james-lovelock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/homage-to-james-lovelock/</guid>
      <description>On the occasion of his 100th birthday, what to do?  Funny: i had just been thinking of the man, when YouTube’s recommendation engine (whose advice i only take while making breakfast, as a rule) threw me this selection- James Lovelock CCLS2019 -from the Cambridge Climate Lecture Series. Turned out to be a discussion about JL and his theories, with the great man only present via 3 short video segments, so for much of the rest, i paid only partial attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABOUT: rf1,Dev</title>
      <link>/post/about-rf1-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about-rf1-dev/</guid>
      <description>At this point i have to say: i’m feeling good right now, because it seems like i have finally found a way to cultivate the habit of writing in a form that works for me personally, can support my work on the farm, and can (eventually) reach a wider audience to achieve a (eventually) growing measure of collective impact… And the foundation of this approach is right here rf1,Dev blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embed Photo album from IMGUR</title>
      <link>/post/embed-photo-album-from-imgur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/embed-photo-album-from-imgur/</guid>
      <description>Mediterranean Food Forest, January 2018   So that’s how it shows up, when you just copy embed code from an Imgur album (kinda hard to find: look just below comment section on last image in the post, that row of social media sharing icons, under the … at far RH end of the line), and just paste the code directly into a Blogdown post. It doesn’t give you a gallery widget on your own site; just a view of the first image w/ caption, that is linked to the full album on Imgur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting Content</title>
      <link>/post/deleting-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deleting-content/</guid>
      <description>The “Blogdown” package to RStudio provides a nice easy UI (i.e. its “Addins”&#34; menu) to push content thru Hugo to the web (via Github and Netlify)… But it has no affordance for the deletion of posts; for this you must go into the Hugo filesystem… Not so easy as i had hoped, alas, but doable. Here’s how:
In RStudio’s file browswer, navigate to /content/post/ , tick box of content item(s) you want gone, and click Delete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instagram embed</title>
      <link>/post/instagram-embed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/instagram-embed/</guid>
      <description>Followihg advice in this article, here is how to share photos from Instagram. First find the image you want on Instagram site, click the share link, and select “copy link” to get the URL, where you can find the ID code of image embedded. Take that code, and use it as argument in the following shortcodes:
   View this post on Instagram        Come be a part of our team!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweet embedding</title>
      <link>/post/tweet-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tweet-embedding/</guid>
      <description>Following advice in this article, here is how to embed a tweet. First, get the URL of the tweet, get the ID of tweet from its URL (i.e. “Copy link to tweet” from the “more” dropdown arrow in top RH corner of tweet display on twitter), and input that as argument in the following shortcode:
Excited to say that our pub is out! How #openscience #datascience #rstats has improved our science https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Links: the wiki way(?)</title>
      <link>/post/reference-links-the-wiki-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reference-links-the-wiki-way/</guid>
      <description> This is about creating a shorthand so i don’t have to type out the full web address of a certain resource, every time i want to point to it.
Testing Reference Links So here’s a list of those:
 The Farm’s website Walt’s ReFarm Blog Walt’s GitHub Pages site  And that’s how it looks
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomy Development</title>
      <link>/post/taxonomy-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/taxonomy-development/</guid>
      <description>To make this site into a useful rsource, even just (especially!) for myself, i need a taxonomy (i.e. Categories and Tags, essentially… Plus any ancillary elements in the site navigation: menu bar, sidebar, naming conventions, etc.) that will make it easy to find (i.e. search and filter) content whenever i need it quickly.
Key concepts under consideration:  Categories are mandatory and mutually exclusive; each post must be assigned to one and only one category  cool: just discovered i can change a cat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Case template</title>
      <link>/post/use-case-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/use-case-template/</guid>
      <description> Use Case 1: (Target) Title (Type)  Primary Actor: User Scope: Software system Level: Summary / User Goal  Main success scenario: … … …   Extensions:  1a. … 3a. … 3b. …   Variations: 2’. …
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow for Writing</title>
      <link>/post/workflow-for-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workflow-for-writing/</guid>
      <description>Key design goal here is “notational velocity” -to capture ideas at speed of thought, and implement them before all the motivation is gone- and for this, my primary working tool is an outliner…. So i’m going to use headings.
Main Success Scenario Writing in DynaList  Create post in Blogdown  Paste in content from DynaList; work it over in  Text editing in Atom Let’s test these invisible links: to my Github, to VdL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube video embed</title>
      <link>/post/video-embed-using-shortcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/video-embed-using-shortcode/</guid>
      <description>Following online tutorial, here’s that paragliding video Pete shot yesterday:
blogdown::shortcode(&amp;quot;youtube&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;yClRNHefT1M&amp;quot;)   There: how does that show up? Here’s another way to do, from goHugo site:
  Ah: that one works better -the code is obscured (NB: i followed text of article, not the video kid, because his &amp;lt;&amp;gt; bracketing arguments didn’t work; instead it was % signs bracketing arguments that worked)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merlin Mann’s advice</title>
      <link>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/merlin-mann-s-advice/</guid>
      <description>Best advice i ever heard for wanna be bloggers came from a guy whose stuff i used to lap up eagerly, every morsel he ever released, until he went silent quite some time ago (he’s still alive -i’ve checked- i think he just got tired of his own schtick). The man is Merlin Mann, and this came from a presentation he did entitled “How to Blog” -which video i did see, a good few years ago; can’t find it now, but i did find his SlideShare deck -notes from which are cribbed below, because i don’t wanna lose this stuff, it’s important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplan, tests, results</title>
      <link>/post/workplan-tests-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workplan-tests-results/</guid>
      <description>Copied over, from a .md file to .rmd
Tests/ Results  Create a new post, with a new author (me) -CHECK edit metadata: roll back create date 1 day -CHECK  it works, if you tick the box to change slug, etc. (is how i screwed up last blog3)  changed author attribution -CHECK -PORTED TO BLOG2  put w_avatar.png in the /themes/Mainroad/static/img folder (alongside default avatar.png)  NB: it got copied (dupe) to /public/img/ folder, when i served the site  changed config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/learn-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learn-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Between Markdown and RMarkdown -and Pandoc and CommonMark and all the site-specific flavors: GitHub, StackExchange, reddit, etc. - i am really confused as to which to learn. The starting point, it seems to me, should be the highest COMMON denominator -which, given all these variants, is probably a pretty small set, i reckon (Gruber&amp;rsquo;s maybe?) Anyway: I post below the Help file from MacDown, the desktop tool i find handiest for testing my markdown; let&amp;rsquo;s compare how Hugo parses this with how MacDown does, and see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything to worry about here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit in which we do</title>
      <link>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-spirit-in-which-we-do/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It matters not what you do so much as the spirit in which you do it&amp;rdquo;
a little brown man in a bedsheet, can&amp;rsquo;t remember which one
Once upon a time, i fell in love with a woman -and when it became quite serious, i got a hand-written letter from this woman&amp;rsquo;s best friend, in which she wrote: &amp;ldquo;This woman you claim to love, she is like fine crystal: Beautiful, as you know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown testing</title>
      <link>/post/r-markdown-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-markdown-testing/</guid>
      <description>So what’s the diff, .Rmd vs .md? Let’s see…
is this a line of commentary? Yup, it is -that is to say, collapsible, and does not execute as code- but it does show up as header in blog… And it can have any number of hashtags, which do control size of header.
so here’s another line of commentary, with 3 hashtags and here’s the text that is contained
 and here’s another such so i can have anothe line of text… &amp;gt;and i can write a code block like this see how cool that is?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this first iteration of the ReFarmer.Net website -at this point a farm-diary in the form of a simple blog, but soon to develop into a network resource for all those interested in Regenerative Agriculture, Permaculture, AgroForestry, AgroEcology and Holistic Management.
Background I&amp;rsquo;m Walt, 1&amp;frasl;2 of the husband/wife team that owns Quinta do Vale da Lama, a 43ha (100 acre) farm at the eastern end of Lagos municipality, Algarve province of Portugal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo</title>
      <link>/blogdownhowto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogdownhowto/</guid>
      <description>Mainly for my FutureSelf, but also for any interested party, this is a little HowTo explainer about some useful but non-obvious features of BlogDown that i may not remember in the moment how to use -so i can get back up to speed on it quickly.
Scope This is not intended as comprehensive documentation -for that, see [references] below, but rather a form of scaffolding that should serve for now, and grow as i learn new methods that i expect to be using more in future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>