<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ReFarmer.Net</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ReFarmer.Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>REAL Organic Standards</title>
      <link>/post/real-organic-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/real-organic-standards/</guid>
      <description>While government-approved organic certification standards are a good thing to have, they are by no means a guarantee that the produce under the label is of the highest nutritional quality. Indeed, as anyone who&amp;rsquo;s seen the film &amp;ldquo;Keeping the Soil in Organic&amp;rdquo; must admit, the standard -at least in USA (i.e. USDA Ceritified Organic)- is so broad as to admit of some very unhealthful practices&amp;hellip; And because those practices are essential to the profitiability of those big agri-businesses that have lobbied successfully to protect them, they are in fact coming to increasingly dominate the organic food supply chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture, 10 years into it</title>
      <link>/post/permaculture-10-years-into-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/permaculture-10-years-into-it/</guid>
      <description>Since hosting our first PDC (Permaculture Design Course) here on the farm some 10 years ago, and having since then gained a measure of fame for our applications of this particular design science, i want to take a few moments here for celebration and critical reflection on that experience.
One project in particular stands out for me as reflecting pretty much the entire rainbow of possibilities: the light, the dark, and everything in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paragliding Cordoama</title>
      <link>/post/paragliding-cordoama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/paragliding-cordoama/</guid>
      <description>A nice cool morning, so i finished sheet-mulching &amp;amp; composting the 3rd of 3 beds today&amp;hellip; But then as sky remained overcast, with a moderate breeze out of NNW, it occurred to me that perhaps the wind would be hitting Cordoama beach just about right. So i took a chance -and bagged a nice 90min flight at my favorite site in all the world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReFarming both Landscape and InfoScape</title>
      <link>/post/refarming-both-landscape-and-infoscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/refarming-both-landscape-and-infoscape/</guid>
      <description>This blogging (given such power tools) takes so little effort&amp;hellip; So why has it been so many weeks since last post?
No excuse, but it does seem like quite a stretch these days, between all i&amp;rsquo;ve got to do on the ground AND &amp;ldquo;in the air,&amp;rdquo; to to speak -i.e. the infosphere. Typically, i am so bushed from the former sort of work that, whenever i sit down at computer, i&amp;rsquo;ve little attention for anything much beyond essential tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bionutrient Food Association</title>
      <link>/post/bionutrient-food-association/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bionutrient-food-association/</guid>
      <description>Enchanted by &amp;ldquo;The Shiny Object,&amp;rdquo; as Dan Kittredge puts it so well in this video, i enquired of the BFA as to the prospects of getting a Bionutrient Meter over here in Portugal&amp;hellip; But in the end, my decision to form a local chapter is grounded in my assessment that this organisation has what it takes to achieve Collective Impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating… Life!</title>
      <link>/post/celebrating-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/celebrating-life/</guid>
      <description>The life of a ReFarmer tends to be so busy, one loses all perspective at times. So: here i am, &amp;ldquo;up before the chickens,&amp;rdquo; as it were -often the only time i can find in a day to address the pile of unanswered emails- when the long list in my inbox went all fuzzy, so i couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to focus, and i found myself staring motionless at the screen so long, my screensaver kicked in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farm OS</title>
      <link>/post/farm-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/farm-os/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken a bit of doing -tho less pain that i expected, thanks to good help of Developer Mike Stenta [1]- but i finally got an instance of Farm OS loaded up with all the landplots on our farm, at least in terms of high-level definitions. I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a visitor account with read-only privs at https://vdl.farmos.net/farm/areas (login/pass = Visit0r/Visit0r), so you can check out the interface and browse around the data (including interactive map), if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holistic Planned Grazing 1</title>
      <link>/post/holistic-planned-grazing-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/holistic-planned-grazing-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Baahhh -where&amp;rsquo;d she go, my little lamb?!&amp;rdquo;
Easy as it is to lose a sheep in the forest of mums now in flower, these sheep don&amp;rsquo;t actually seem to perturbed by the lack of visibility, as they are too busy eating. These days, it is easy enough to contain them in the paddock using this &amp;ldquo;Smart Fence&amp;rdquo; which is really just quickly deployed perimeter in the form of 3 wires (charged via mains or solar battery) spooled-out around a set of step-in stakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Photo Blogging Workflow, Challenges</title>
      <link>/post/mobile-photo-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mobile-photo-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Could THE solution to mobile image management finally be at hand? THE answer (TLDR) is: NO.
My more nuanced answer (if you&amp;rsquo;ve got the patience for it) is: If techology is defined, per Douglas Adams, as &amp;ldquo;stuff that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work right yet,&amp;rdquo; and infrastructure is &amp;ldquo;stuff that works so well, we&amp;rsquo;re not even aware of it,&amp;rdquo; then how this technology will ever evolve into infrastructure, i simply cannot IMAGine. Or, rather: while i could easily imagine how the big players in online media might like to develop such infrastructure and wrap us all up in its fuzzy embrace, i&amp;rsquo;m very clear that this is not a future that i would like to inhabit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbers</title>
      <link>/post/climbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/climbers/</guid>
      <description>To provide some shade on the sunset verandah of our new rammed-earth farm-home, we&amp;rsquo;ve planted some climbers like this around the pillars: What&amp;rsquo;s novel about this plantation is: it&amp;rsquo;s irrigated entirely with greywater from our laundry-to-landscape irrigation system: literally running the effluent from each load of laundry to our choice of 4 different climbers that we&amp;rsquo;ve got planted at the base of each pillar. I had my as to how they might react to the laundry soap -even though we use the most ecological (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GROW Observatory: making an impact</title>
      <link>/post/grow-observatory-making-an-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/grow-observatory-making-an-impact/</guid>
      <description>Since joining this project last August, we&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a whole lot of soil sensors across our landscape and spent more than a few hours collecting and uploading data, without having any real sense of the big picture, i.e.: What is the full scope and distribution of this Citizens Observatory? and what insight can we derive from the data gathered thus far?
Well&amp;hellip; Results are only just starting to come back from The Observatory, but the picture is pretty encouraging already, at least a far as the first question is concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation 1</title>
      <link>/post/data-visualisation-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-visualisation-1/</guid>
      <description>Until i can figure out how this business of Shiny app publishing, i guess i&amp;rsquo;m stuck with the old-school method of saving graphics out of RStudio and pasting them into documents, like this post.
My workflow on this operation is:
 copy the image of plot as visualised in RStudio; paste it into my desktop image editor, to make any needed adjustments; upload it from there to Imgur.com, which is the best online image host i have found; then paste code Imgur provides for my choice of image rendering size into the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app publishing</title>
      <link>/post/shiny-app-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shiny-app-publishing/</guid>
      <description>Met this morning with Franceso (my R dev collaborator and coach), and we got our Shiny app working well enough that i am very keen to publish it on the web. Much easier said than done! It&amp;rsquo;s pretty bandwidth intensive, as it is crunching a pretty large volume of data, and shinyapps.io just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem up to the task.
So we&amp;rsquo;re looking for alternatives. Only one i know about right now is rpubs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging in RStudio</title>
      <link>/post/blogging-in-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blogging-in-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>I started this blog in a hurry back in January… And since then, i forgot how i did it!
Took a bit of rummaging around, to reacquaint myself with all elements of the technology stack, which includes:
 RStudio Blogdown (RStudio addin, output thru Hugo framework, Lithium default theme) Github.com (free account) Netlify.com (another free account, connected to the former)  It then took a few hours of study and play, to get the software configured and myself trained to the point where i can blog as efficiently as in Wordpress -so now i can freely appreciate the significant advantages of this file-based system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>